<?xml version="1.0"?>
	<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
	 <channel>
		<title>Phoronix</title>
		<link>https://www.phoronix.com/</link>
		<description>Linux Hardware Reviews, Performance Benchmarks &amp; Open-Source / Free Software News</description>
		<language>en-us</language>
	  <item>
   <title>FreeBSD 14.2 Beta 1 Released To Work Toward This Next Release</title>
   <link>https://www.phoronix.com/news/FreeBSD-14.2-Beta-1-Released</link>
   <guid>https://www.phoronix.com/news/FreeBSD-14.2-Beta-1-Released</guid>
   <description>FreeBSD 14.2 Beta 1 is out today as the first tagged test snapshot in working toward this newest FreeBSD 14 point release...</description>
   <pubDate>Sat, 02 Nov 2024 15:49:30 -0400</pubDate>
   <dc:creator>Michael Larabel</dc:creator>
  </item>
  <item>
   <title>Cloudflare&#039;s Pingora 0.4 Rust Framework Released With Experimental Windows Support</title>
   <link>https://www.phoronix.com/news/Cloudflare-Pingora-0.4</link>
   <guid>https://www.phoronix.com/news/Cloudflare-Pingora-0.4</guid>
   <description>Cloudflare's Pingora Rust framework that was written as a replacement to Nginx and made publicly open-source earlier this year with a focus on building fast and reliable networked systems is out with its newest feature release...</description>
   <pubDate>Sat, 02 Nov 2024 12:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
   <dc:creator>Michael Larabel</dc:creator>
  </item>
  <item>
   <title>Genode-Based Sculpt OS 24.10 Introduces Multi-Monitor Support</title>
   <link>https://www.phoronix.com/news/Genode-Sculpt-OS-24.10</link>
   <guid>https://www.phoronix.com/news/Genode-Sculpt-OS-24.10</guid>
   <description>Sculpt OS for what has been working to become a general purpose operating system built off the original Genode is out with a new feature release...</description>
   <pubDate>Sat, 02 Nov 2024 08:44:15 -0400</pubDate>
   <dc:creator>Michael Larabel</dc:creator>
  </item>
  <item>
   <title>Intel Lands VVC VA-API Hardware Decoding Into FFmpeg</title>
   <link>https://www.phoronix.com/news/VVC-VA-API-FFmpeg-Decode</link>
   <guid>https://www.phoronix.com/news/VVC-VA-API-FFmpeg-Decode</guid>
   <description>Intel has integrated VVC VA-API hardware accelerated decoding support into the widely-used FFmpeg multimedia library...</description>
   <pubDate>Sat, 02 Nov 2024 06:49:46 -0400</pubDate>
   <dc:creator>Michael Larabel</dc:creator>
  </item>
  <item>
   <title>KDE Will Nicely Notify You When Apps Are Being Killed Due To Out-Of-Memory</title>
   <link>https://www.phoronix.com/news/KDE-Plasma-OOM-Notifications</link>
   <guid>https://www.phoronix.com/news/KDE-Plasma-OOM-Notifications</guid>
   <description>KDE developer Nate Graham is out with his weekly development summary of interesting KDE changes in closing out October...</description>
   <pubDate>Sat, 02 Nov 2024 06:30:59 -0400</pubDate>
   <dc:creator>Michael Larabel</dc:creator>
  </item>
  <item>
   <title>Vulkan 1.3.301 Released With New Extension For HDR Vivid</title>
   <link>https://www.phoronix.com/news/Vulkan-1.3.301-HDR-Vivid</link>
   <guid>https://www.phoronix.com/news/Vulkan-1.3.301-HDR-Vivid</guid>
   <description>Vulkan 1.3.301 was published on Friday with the lone new extension this release being a rare contribution from Huawei adding HDR Vivid support with VK_HUAWEI_hdr_vivid...</description>
   <pubDate>Sat, 02 Nov 2024 06:20:00 -0400</pubDate>
   <dc:creator>Michael Larabel</dc:creator>
  </item>
  <item>
   <title>Xfce 4.20 Pre1 Pre-Release Published For Testing</title>
   <link>https://www.phoronix.com/news/Xfce-4.20-Pre1-Released</link>
   <guid>https://www.phoronix.com/news/Xfce-4.20-Pre1-Released</guid>
   <description>Right on schedule for releasing the Xfce 4.20 desktop in December, the "Pre1" pre-release was posted on Friday for testing...</description>
   <pubDate>Sat, 02 Nov 2024 06:03:31 -0400</pubDate>
   <dc:creator>Michael Larabel</dc:creator>
  </item>
  <item>
   <title>Steam On Linux Marketshare Hits 2.0% For October, AMD CPU Use By Linux Gamers Approaches 75%</title>
   <link>https://www.phoronix.com/news/Steam-October-2024-Numbers</link>
   <guid>https://www.phoronix.com/news/Steam-October-2024-Numbers</guid>
   <description>Earlier this year and through July Steam on Linux was enjoying above a 2% marketshare thanks to the success of the Arch Linux powered SteamOS and Steam Deck offerings. But then for August and September Steam on Linux use was below 2%. After a 0.13% rise in October, Steam on Linux is back to sitting at a 2.00% marketshare...</description>
   <pubDate>Fri, 01 Nov 2024 20:12:57 -0400</pubDate>
   <dc:creator>Michael Larabel</dc:creator>
  </item>
  <item>
   <title>Wine 10.0 Release Plans Aim For Mid-January Release</title>
   <link>https://www.phoronix.com/news/Wine-10.0-Release-Plans</link>
   <guid>https://www.phoronix.com/news/Wine-10.0-Release-Plans</guid>
   <description>Wine project leader Alexandre Julliard has laid out plans for releasing Wine 10.0 around mid-January as the annual stable release for this open-source software to run Windows applications and games on Linux and other platforms...</description>
   <pubDate>Fri, 01 Nov 2024 13:28:03 -0400</pubDate>
   <dc:creator>Michael Larabel</dc:creator>
  </item>
  <item>
   <title>Ubuntu&#039;s Great Mainline Kernel PPA Hasn&#039;t Been Working Since Mid-September</title>
   <link>https://www.phoronix.com/news/Ubuntu-Mainline-PPA-2024-Break</link>
   <guid>https://www.phoronix.com/news/Ubuntu-Mainline-PPA-2024-Break</guid>
   <description>One of the very convenient features for Ubuntu Linux users who want to run the very newest upstream kernel releases or simply test a new kernel build for verifying bug fixes or functionality has been the Ubuntu Mainline Kernel PPA. It's been around for years, backed by Canonical, and very convenient for fetching pre-built AArch64 / ARM / POWER / RISC-V / x86_64 kernel binaries as Debian packages... With options of stable/test kernel versions as well as daily packages. Sadly, it's been broken once again and has been in that manner since mid-September...</description>
   <pubDate>Fri, 01 Nov 2024 11:54:06 -0400</pubDate>
   <dc:creator>Michael Larabel</dc:creator>
  </item>
  <item>
   <title>Valve Engineer Fixes Massive Performance Issue For RADV Driver With AMD FSR2 Sample</title>
   <link>https://www.phoronix.com/news/AMD-FSR2-Mesa-24.3-Fix</link>
   <guid>https://www.phoronix.com/news/AMD-FSR2-Mesa-24.3-Fix</guid>
   <description>With the upcoming Mesa 24.3 release there is a huge improvement coming for those using the RADV Radeon Vulkan driver with the AMD FidelityFX Super Resolution 2 sample app...</description>
   <pubDate>Fri, 01 Nov 2024 10:26:15 -0400</pubDate>
   <dc:creator>Michael Larabel</dc:creator>
  </item>
  <item>
   <title>Google Chrome/Chromium Lands linux_drm_syncobj_v1 For Wayland Explicit Sync</title>
   <link>https://www.phoronix.com/news/Google-Chrome-linux-drm-syncobj</link>
   <guid>https://www.phoronix.com/news/Google-Chrome-linux-drm-syncobj</guid>
   <description>The Google Chrome/Chromium web browser code has merged support for linux_drm_syncobj_v1 as the modern Wayland protocol for explicit buffer synchronization...</description>
   <pubDate>Fri, 01 Nov 2024 09:31:24 -0400</pubDate>
   <dc:creator>Michael Larabel</dc:creator>
  </item>
  <item>
   <title>New Intel Diamond Rapids Patch For GCC Confirms AVX10.2-512, APX &amp; Other ISA Features</title>
   <link>https://www.phoronix.com/news/Intel-Diamond-Rapids-APX-AVX10</link>
   <guid>https://www.phoronix.com/news/Intel-Diamond-Rapids-APX-AVX10</guid>
   <description>Intel software engineers have been very busy recently with upstreaming various elements of support into the Linux kernel, open-source compilers and more for the next-generation Xeon Diamond Rapids processors. Following the recent GCC prep patches for Diamond Rapids to work on the ISA additions around AMX-AVX512, AMX-FP8, AMX-FP32, and others, a new patch was posted today for actually exposing the "-march=diamondrapids" compiler target and in turn confirming all of the new ISA capabilities...</description>
   <pubDate>Fri, 01 Nov 2024 07:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
   <dc:creator>Michael Larabel</dc:creator>
  </item>
  <item>
   <title>Intel Arrow Lake, AMD EPYC Turin &amp; Linux Kernel Drama Made For An Interesting October</title>
   <link>https://www.phoronix.com/news/October-2024-Highlights</link>
   <guid>https://www.phoronix.com/news/October-2024-Highlights</guid>
   <description>October is now in the books after writing 247 original news articles and another 24 Linux hardware reviews / featured multi-page benchmark articles. From the launches of Intel Arrow Lake and AMD EPYC 9005 to other interesting new hardware, the Russian Linux kernel drama, Linux 6.12 developments and early Linux 6.13 patches queuing in "-next" branches, October was an interesting month both for hardware and open-source software...</description>
   <pubDate>Fri, 01 Nov 2024 06:34:00 -0400</pubDate>
   <dc:creator>Michael Larabel</dc:creator>
  </item>
  <item>
   <title>Ubuntu Hoping To Remove Qt 5 Before Ubuntu 26.04 LTS</title>
   <link>https://www.phoronix.com/news/Ubuntu-Hopes-Removing-Qt-5</link>
   <guid>https://www.phoronix.com/news/Ubuntu-Hopes-Removing-Qt-5</guid>
   <description>Ubuntu developer Simon Quigley laid out the plans for hoping Ubuntu packages will move from Qt 5 to Qt 6 so that by the time of the Ubuntu 26.04 LTS cycle in early 2026 that the older version of this graphical toolkit can be removed...</description>
   <pubDate>Fri, 01 Nov 2024 06:24:21 -0400</pubDate>
   <dc:creator>Michael Larabel</dc:creator>
  </item>
  <item>
   <title>Miriway 24.10 Compositor Adds systemd Integration, DE-Specific Configurations</title>
   <link>https://www.phoronix.com/news/Miriway-24.10-Released</link>
   <guid>https://www.phoronix.com/news/Miriway-24.10-Released</guid>
   <description>Miriway 24.10 was released on Halloween as the newest version of this Mir-based Wayland compositor. Miriway is developed by Canonical/Ubuntu developers as a compositor for other desktops like Xfce, MATE, LXQt and others as a way to ease their migration path to Wayland...</description>
   <pubDate>Fri, 01 Nov 2024 06:13:37 -0400</pubDate>
   <dc:creator>Michael Larabel</dc:creator>
  </item>
  <item>
   <title>Bcachefs Reining In Bugs: Test Dashboard Failures Drop By 40% Over Last Month</title>
   <link>https://www.phoronix.com/news/Bcachefs-Failures-Drop-40p</link>
   <guid>https://www.phoronix.com/news/Bcachefs-Failures-Drop-40p</guid>
   <description>As part of the latest Bcachefs fixes pull request, lead developer Kent Overstreet has provided an update on the bug situation for this advanced copy-on-write open-source file-system...</description>
   <pubDate>Fri, 01 Nov 2024 06:08:09 -0400</pubDate>
   <dc:creator>Michael Larabel</dc:creator>
  </item>
  <item>
   <title>Academy Software Foundation Releases OpenVDB 12.0 Under New License</title>
   <link>https://www.phoronix.com/news/ASF-OpenVDB-12.0</link>
   <guid>https://www.phoronix.com/news/ASF-OpenVDB-12.0</guid>
   <description>The Academy Software Foundation that is made up of many different vendors released OpenVDB 12.0 as the newest major release to this sparse volume data structure library and tooling that is an Academy Award winning library started by DreamWorks Animation...</description>
   <pubDate>Fri, 01 Nov 2024 05:53:42 -0400</pubDate>
   <dc:creator>Michael Larabel</dc:creator>
  </item>
  <item>
   <title>VMware Workstation Shifting From Proprietary Code To Using Upstream KVM</title>
   <link>https://www.phoronix.com/news/VMware-Workstation-KVM</link>
   <guid>https://www.phoronix.com/news/VMware-Workstation-KVM</guid>
   <description>This isn't an off-schedule April Fools' Joke or anything like that but an exciting sign of the times: VMware Workstation will be shifting off its proprietary base and onto leveraging the upstream Linux Kernel-based Virtual Machine (KVM) for virtualization needs moving forward...</description>
   <pubDate>Thu, 31 Oct 2024 20:57:29 -0400</pubDate>
   <dc:creator>Michael Larabel</dc:creator>
  </item>
  <item>
   <title>COSMIC Desktop Alpha 3 Released With More Enhancements</title>
   <link>https://www.phoronix.com/news/COSMIC-Desktop-Alpha-3</link>
   <guid>https://www.phoronix.com/news/COSMIC-Desktop-Alpha-3</guid>
   <description>As a nice Halloween treat for Linux desktop users, System76 has published their third alpha version of the Rust-written COSMIC desktop environment...</description>
   <pubDate>Thu, 31 Oct 2024 20:48:26 -0400</pubDate>
   <dc:creator>Michael Larabel</dc:creator>
  </item>
  <item>
   <title>AMD EPYC 9655 Benchmarks Show The Terrific Generational Gains With 5th Gen EPYC</title>
   <link>https://www.phoronix.com/review/amd-epyc-9655</link>
   <guid>https://www.phoronix.com/review/amd-epyc-9655</guid>
   <description>With the AMD EPYC 9005 &quot;Turin&quot; series launch earlier this month there was launch-day benchmark review results for the EPYC 9575F, EPYC 9755, and EPYC 9965 processors in looking at that frequency optimized SKU, the new flagship 128-core Turin &quot;classic&quot; core model, and the new flagship 192-core Turin &quot;dense&quot; core SKU, respectively. That&#039;s interesting for looking at the new 5th Gen AMD EPYC top-end wares but in comparing to 4th Gen EPYC also means higher core counts at the top-end. In being curious about the core-for-core advantages of 5th Gen EPYC, I managed to get my hands on the AMD EPYC 9655 processors for seeing how that model compares to the prior AMD EPYC 9654 &quot;Genoa&quot; flagship model. Here&#039;s a look today at how the AMD EPYC 9655 1P/2P 96-core processor compares to the prior EPYC 9654 flagship.</description>
   <pubDate>Thu, 31 Oct 2024 12:26:21 -0400</pubDate>
   <dc:creator>Michael Larabel</dc:creator>
  </item>
  <item>
   <title>AMD Formally Announces Ryzen 7 9800X3D Specs - Should Be Great For Linux Creators</title>
   <link>https://www.phoronix.com/news/AMD-Ryzen-7-9800X3D</link>
   <guid>https://www.phoronix.com/news/AMD-Ryzen-7-9800X3D</guid>
   <description>AMD has been teasing the Ryzen 9000X3D Zen 5 CPUs with 3D V-Cache and today they formally announced the specs of the Ryzen 7 9800X3D processor that will begin shipping 7 November...</description>
   <pubDate>Thu, 31 Oct 2024 09:47:48 -0400</pubDate>
   <dc:creator>Michael Larabel</dc:creator>
  </item>
  <item>
   <title>Fedora Stakeholders Debate Idea Of &quot;-O3&quot; Optimized Packages</title>
   <link>https://www.phoronix.com/news/Fedora-Debates-O3-Packages</link>
   <guid>https://www.phoronix.com/news/Fedora-Debates-O3-Packages</guid>
   <description>Following the announcement yesterday that Ubuntu 25.04 will default to the -O3 optimization level with GCC for its Debian package builds, Fedora stakeholders have begun debating the merits of switching to the -O3 optimization level or not instead of the existing -O2 optimization level default...</description>
   <pubDate>Thu, 31 Oct 2024 09:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
   <dc:creator>Michael Larabel</dc:creator>
  </item>
  <item>
   <title>Linus Torvalds Lands A 2.6% Performance Improvement With Minor Linux Kernel Patch</title>
   <link>https://www.phoronix.com/news/Linus-2.6p-Faster-Scale-Patch</link>
   <guid>https://www.phoronix.com/news/Linus-2.6p-Faster-Scale-Patch</guid>
   <description>Linus Torvalds merged a patch on Wednesday that he authored that with reworking a few lines of code is able to score a 2.6% improvement within Intel's well-exercise "will it scale" per-thread-ops benchmark test case...</description>
   <pubDate>Thu, 31 Oct 2024 07:10:00 -0400</pubDate>
   <dc:creator>Michael Larabel</dc:creator>
  </item>
  <item>
   <title>AMX-FP8 Support Upstreamed Into LLVM For Intel Diamond Rapids</title>
   <link>https://www.phoronix.com/news/Intel-AMX-FP8-In-LLVM</link>
   <guid>https://www.phoronix.com/news/Intel-AMX-FP8-In-LLVM</guid>
   <description>Intel compiler engineer Feng Zou has upstreamed AMX-FP8 support into the LLVM compiler stack. This FP8 extension to the Advanced Matrix Extensions (AMX) is coming with next-gen Diamond Rapids processors alongside other new ISA extensions...</description>
   <pubDate>Thu, 31 Oct 2024 06:43:03 -0400</pubDate>
   <dc:creator>Michael Larabel</dc:creator>
  </item>
  <item>
   <title>SUSE&#039;s Agama Installer Adds QR Code To The Console &amp; Other Improvements</title>
   <link>https://www.phoronix.com/news/SUSE-Agama-10-Installer</link>
   <guid>https://www.phoronix.com/news/SUSE-Agama-10-Installer</guid>
   <description>SUSE's Agama OS installer 10 was recently released as the newest feature iteration for this next-gen OS installer for SUSE/openSUSE...</description>
   <pubDate>Thu, 31 Oct 2024 06:33:00 -0400</pubDate>
   <dc:creator>Michael Larabel</dc:creator>
  </item>
  <item>
   <title>SVT-AV1 2.3 Brings More Performance Improvements: AVX-512 &amp; LTO By Default, More Tuning</title>
   <link>https://www.phoronix.com/news/SVT-AV1-2.3</link>
   <guid>https://www.phoronix.com/news/SVT-AV1-2.3</guid>
   <description>SVT-AV1 2.3 is now available as the newest feature release to this leading open-source AV1 encoder. With SVT-AV1 2.3 there are yet more performance improvements...</description>
   <pubDate>Thu, 31 Oct 2024 06:20:15 -0400</pubDate>
   <dc:creator>Michael Larabel</dc:creator>
  </item>
  <item>
   <title>AMDVLK 2024.Q4.1 Adds A Few More Vulkan Extensions</title>
   <link>https://www.phoronix.com/news/AMDVLK-2024.Q4.1-Released</link>
   <guid>https://www.phoronix.com/news/AMDVLK-2024.Q4.1-Released</guid>
   <description>One month has passed since the AMDVLK 2024.Q3.3 driver release while today has brought the AMDVLK 2024.Q4.1 release with a few new Vulkan API extensions...</description>
   <pubDate>Thu, 31 Oct 2024 06:03:41 -0400</pubDate>
   <dc:creator>Michael Larabel</dc:creator>
  </item>
  <item>
   <title>AMD &quot;Cleaner Shader&quot; Coming For GFX11.0.3 GPUs To Help Ensure User/App Isolation</title>
   <link>https://www.phoronix.com/news/AMD-Cleaner-Shader-GFX11.0.3</link>
   <guid>https://www.phoronix.com/news/AMD-Cleaner-Shader-GFX11.0.3</guid>
   <description>A new patch posted today for the AMDGPU Linux kernel graphics driver is introducing a "cleaner shader" explicitly for GFX11.0.3 GPUs like the Radeon 780M integrated graphics to help ensure that there is sufficient data isolation between different workloads running on the GPUs. The motivation isn't clear if there is some GFX11.0.3 security vulnerability, some AMD Linux customer particularly concerned about security on said GPUs, or some other motivation for focusing this latest cleaner shader work on GFX11.0.3 hardware...</description>
   <pubDate>Wed, 30 Oct 2024 20:27:52 -0400</pubDate>
   <dc:creator>Michael Larabel</dc:creator>
  </item>
  <item>
   <title>Ubuntu 25.04 &quot;Plucky Puffin&quot; Development Opens - Defaulting To -O3 Optimizations</title>
   <link>https://www.phoronix.com/news/Ubuntu-25.04-Plucky-Puffin</link>
   <guid>https://www.phoronix.com/news/Ubuntu-25.04-Plucky-Puffin</guid>
   <description>Canonical has announced the formal state of the Ubuntu 25.04 "Plucky Puffin" development. Among other early changes are now defaulting to -O3 compiler optimizations rather than the default -O2 optimization level when building Debian packages...</description>
   <pubDate>Wed, 30 Oct 2024 16:02:39 -0400</pubDate>
   <dc:creator>Michael Larabel</dc:creator>
  </item>
  <item>
   <title>Benchmarks Of Google&#039;s Axion Arm-based CPU: Competitive Performance &amp; Compelling Value</title>
   <link>https://www.phoronix.com/review/google-axion-c4a</link>
   <guid>https://www.phoronix.com/review/google-axion-c4a</guid>
   <description>Earlier this year Google announced Axion as their first Arm-based CPU for the Google Cloud. Today already they are taking Axion to general availability with the new C4A instances. These new C4A instances are advertised as offering up to 50% better performance and up to 60% better energy efficiency than their current generation x86 instance types. In this article are some of the first public independent performance benchmarks of the Google Axion CPU along with comparing to existing GCE Arm and x86_64 instance types.</description>
   <pubDate>Wed, 30 Oct 2024 12:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
   <dc:creator>Michael Larabel</dc:creator>
  </item>
  <item>
   <title>OpenPaX Announced As &quot;Open-Source Alternative To GrSecurity&quot; With Free Kernel Patch</title>
   <link>https://www.phoronix.com/news/Edera-OpenPaX-Announced</link>
   <guid>https://www.phoronix.com/news/Edera-OpenPaX-Announced</guid>
   <description>Enterprise security firm Edera today is announcing OpenPaX that they promoted in their advance press notice as a "new open-source alternative to GrSecurity." GrSecurity being the firm focused on providing out-of-tree Linux kernel patches focused in the name of security enhancements. With OpenPaX they are open-source and publicly available kernel patch for mitigating common memory safety errors and other system hardening...</description>
   <pubDate>Wed, 30 Oct 2024 11:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
   <dc:creator>Michael Larabel</dc:creator>
  </item>
</channel>
	</rss>